monolithicpower.com 2019-07-24

# Privacy Policy

Monolithic Power Systems (" **MPS** ") is committed to honoring the privacy of its users. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy and how we treat information that we collect through your use of our website (located at [https://www.monolithicpower.com](https://www.monolithicpower.com/)) (the " **Website** "). This Privacy Policy is governed by our Website Terms of Use. By using the Website, you consent to the data practices prescribed in this Privacy Policy.

**Information Collection**

" **Personally Identifiable Information** " means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, without limitation, first and last name, home or other physical address, email address, phone number or other contact information, whether at work or at home. MPS collects Personally Identifiable Information from you when you access the Website and through the use of request forms that may be submitted on the Website. Personally Identifiable Information may include, without limitation, information obtained from your device, such as IP address and geo-location data. It may also include information provided to us voluntarily by you, in order to complete a purchase on the Website - your name, email address, home address, payment information (credit card number, bank account and other types of financial information). We also collect your information when you respond to communications from us, contact our support, or communicate with us via email, the Website or through any online platform. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but in such case you might not be able to take advantage of certain features or services that we offer. We do not collect sensitive data such as social security numbers.

In order to enhance the functionality of MPS' services and Website, MPS also collects non-personal, non-identifiable information, such as your aggregated usage information and technical information transmitted by your device, including usage logs, certain software and hardware information (e.g., the type of browser and operating system your device uses, language preference, access time and the domain name of the website from which you linked to the Website, etc.) (collectively, " **Non-Personal Information** ").

**Information Use**

MPS uses the Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personal Information it collects from you to:

a) provide you with information regarding our products and promotions;,

b) support your use of our products and services;

c) perform research or to conduct analytics in order to improve and customize our services to your needs;

d) prevent fraudulent or illegal activity; and

e) investigate violations and enforce our policies and, as required by law, regulation or other governmental authority, or to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process or respond to a government request.

**Disclosure; Sharing of Personally Identifiable Information**

Personally Identifiable Information as well as any other information collected on the Website may be disclosed to our staff and/or agents, so that they can contact you regarding our products, services or promotional offers, respond to your requests, provide certain services to you and operate the Website and the programs offered on it.

MPS does not rent, sell or share Personally Identifiable Information it collects about you to or with third parties. Information collected from you is only used to complete and support your purchases from and use of the Website and to comply with any requirements of law. MPS may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on MPS or the Website; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of MPS or enforce MPS' policies; or (3) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of MPS, its websites or the public. If MPS should ever file for bankruptcy or merge with another company, we may sell the information you provide to us on the Website to a third party or share your Personally Identifiable Information with any company with whom we merge.

**Retention and Update of Information**

We allow you to view the information you provided during registration to the Website and to alter any data, inaccuracies or errors relating to such information through the Website.

Please note that information that you have provided us as part of your registration to a marketing list cannot be updated online. If you wish to correct, update or amend such information, please contact us at [contactinfo@monolithicpower.com](mailto:contactinfo@monolithicpower.com) . For opting out of our marketing list, please see the "Communications" section below.

Please note that unless you instruct us otherwise, we will retain your information for as long as we deem necessary to provide you with our services, process and complete transactions, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our policies. We may rectify, replenish or remove incomplete or inaccurate information, at any time and at our own discretion.

**Cookies**

Our Website uses cookies as described below:

A "cookie" is a small piece of information that a website assigns to your device while you are viewing a website. Cookies are very helpful and can be used for various different purposes. These purposes include allowing you to navigate between pages efficiently, enable automatic activation of certain features, remembering your preferences and making the interaction between you and our services quicker and easier. Cookies are also used to compile statistical data on your use of our services.

Our website uses the following types of cookies:

'session cookies' which are stored only temporarily during a browsing session in order to allow normal use of the system and are deleted from your device when the browser is closed;

'persistent cookies' which are saved on your computer for a fixed period and are not deleted when the browser is closed. Such cookies are read only by our Website and used where we need to know who you are for repeat visits—for example, to allow us to store your preferences for your next sign-in;

'third party cookies' which are set by other online services who run content on the page you are viewing—for example, by third party analytics companies who analyze our web access, or are used to deliver tailored offers and advertisements to you, based on your derived interests.

Cookies usually do not contain any information that personally identifies you, but Personal Information that we store about you may be linked, by us, to the information stored in or obtained from cookies. You may remove the cookies by following the instructions of your device preferences; however, if you choose to disable cookies, some features of our services may not operate properly and your online experience may be limited.

We also use a tool called “Google Analytics” to collect information about your use of our services. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users access the Website, what pages they visit when they do so, etc. We use the information we get from Google Analytics only to improve our Website. Google Analytics collects the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit sites, rather than your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy.

**Communications**

If you have registered to our marketing list, we may send you marketing emails. By registering, you affirmatively consent to receive such commercial messages on an on-going basis throughout your use of the Website. As a registered member, you can remove your personal information from our mailing list and stop receiving future communication from us by following the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each communication or by emailing us at [unsubscribe@monolithicpower.com](mailto:unsubscribe@monolithicpower.com). Please note that we reserve the right to send you service related communications, including service announcements and administrative messages, relating to your transactions on this Website, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them unless you cancel your account.

**Security**

All Personally Identifiable Information MPS receives directly from you is stored in a password-protected database residing on a secure network behind an active firewall. [We utilize 256-bit Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology to protect payment information when it passes from your computer to our servers over the Internet.] Although we take reasonable steps to safeguard information, you must realize that no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and that we cannot be responsible for the acts of those who gain unauthorized access or abuse our services or Website. We, therefore, cannot guarantee the absolute security of your information or that we will prevent such access.

**Children**

This website is not intended for or directed to persons under the age of 13. Any person who provides their information to MPS through any part of the MPS website represents that they are 13 years of age or older.

**International Transfers**

Since we operate globally, Personally Identifiable Information collected on the Website may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which MPS or its affiliates, subsidiaries, contractors or agents maintain facilities (including countries outside of the European Union) and it may be necessary to transfer your Personally Identifiable Information to any such country. In such instances, we will take steps to ensure that the level of security safeguards implemented with regards to your Personally Identifiable Information is at least as required in your own country. **By using the Website, you consent to any such transfer of your Personally Identifiable Information outside of your country.**

**Consent**

By using this site, you agree to this Privacy Policy. This is our entire and exclusive Privacy Policy and it supersedes any earlier version. Our Terms and Conditions take precedence over any conflicting Privacy Policy provision.

**Legal Disclaimer**

This web site operates “AS-IS” and “AS-AVAILABLE,” without liability of any kind. We are not responsible for events beyond our direct control. This Privacy Policy is governed by the laws of California, excluding conflicts of law principles. Any legal actions against us must be commenced in the Northern District of California within one (1) year after the claim arose, or such action(s) will be barred.

**Updates and Admendments**

We may periodically make changes to this Privacy Policy. It is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy on this page frequently and remain informed about any changes to it, so we encourage you to visit this page often. Your continued use of the Website, following such amendments, constitutes your acknowledgement of and consent to such amendments to the Privacy Policy and your agreement to be bound by the terms of the Privacy Policy, as amended.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions, comments or complaints related to this Privacy Policy, please contact our webmaster at [webmaster@monolithicpower.com](mailto:webmaster@monolithicpower.com)
